Rodney Gauna

Technical Product Manager/Project Manager

rodneygauna@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/rodneygauna/

760-587-0052 • Vista, CA

High-level and talented Technical Product Manager adept in User Experience Design. Lead the Product Design function in an effort to develop customer use cases, personas and scenarios, and interface design. Provide leadership in requirements gathering, interactive design, user testing, and rapid prototyping utilizing Front-End Development. Plan, implement and execute strategy while maintaining daily contact with the software development group to refine and revise product specifications and implementation details. Encourage the team to innovate within the boundaries of market segments.

- Project Management
- Budget Management
- Strategic Planning & Analysis
- Communication

- Product Development
- Agile Methodologies
- Leadership
- Bilingual: English/Spanish
- Market Research
- Product Launch
- User Experience Design
- Complex Problem Solving

Professional Experience

AristaMD • San Diego, CA • June 2021 to Present

Senior Product Manager

- Lead multiple Scrum Teams in planning, developing, and releasing feature updates and new functionality for a telehealth eConsult web-based platform.
- Work closely with development to communicate product status, resolve issues, and ensure high-quality products are delivered in a timely manner.
- Roadmap definition ensure it aligns with the overall company vision, revenue objectives, customer feedback, and
 market analysis. Evangelize the vision constantly to ensure all stakeholders are aligned, have context, and
 understand where we are going.
- Gather analysis of product specifications and enhancements, customer feedback, and market testing for the development of a next-generation product.
- Lead requirements gathering effort on assigned epics as needed consulting with the product team, internal teams, customers, and partners as applicable.
- Create mockups and low-fidelity prototypes; take lead on user experience to develop delightful and thoughtful user flows; works with UX on high-fidelity design.
- Ensure effective rollout of new products and major product updates; package and position ideas and products in ways that uniquely appeal to consumers and serves the needs of all functions.
- Define and measure success for all product features. Reviews and analyzes product metrics to inform strategic and tactical product decisions.
- Serve as an advocate for customers by building impactful personal relationships.
- Collaborate closely with sales, support, and stakeholders to deliver product alignment.

ChiroTouch (Integrated Practice Solutions) • San Diego, CA • February 2018 to May 2021

Group Product Manager

- Manage a team of Senior Product Managers, Product Managers, and Product Owners.
- Functionally manages, organizes, mentors, and leads product managers to achieve strategic goals for product portfolio(s).
- Lead multiple Scrum Teams in planning, developing, and releasing a green-field web-based EHR platform.
- Work closely with development to communicate product status, resolve issues, and ensure high-quality products are delivered in a timely manner.
- Lead and oversaw the implementation of Agile methodology and Scrum practices.

- Roadmap definition ensure it aligns with the overall company vision, revenue objectives, customer feedback, and market analysis. Evangelize the vision constantly to ensure all stakeholders are aligned, have context, and understand where we are going.
- Where there are product or service gaps, determine to buy, build, or partner decisions including the preparation of business cases with ROI/financial projections.
- Gather analysis of product specifications and enhancements, customer feedback, and market testing for the development of a next-generation product.
- Lead requirements gathering effort on assigned epics as needed consulting with the product team, internal teams, customers, and partners as applicable.
- Create mockups and low-fidelity prototypes; take lead on user experience to develop delightful and thoughtful user flows; works with UX on high-fidelity design.
- Ensure effective rollout of new products and major product updates; package and position ideas and products in ways that uniquely appeal to consumers and serves the needs of all functions.
- Define and measure success for all product features. Reviews and analyzes product metrics to inform strategic and tactical product decisions.
- Identifies goals, metrics, and appropriate analytics to measure the performance of the product and its individual features, and makes recommendations and refinements to the product based on learnings.
- Accountable for delivering business objectives. Ensure product timeline, revenue & retention goals are attained.
- Fully understand and implement regulatory and certification requirements and trends that impact offerings. Demonstrate expertise on US Healthcare industry and EHR/Practice Management domain.
- Serve as an advocate for customers by building impactful personal relationships.
- Collaborate closely with sales, support, and stakeholders to deliver product alignment.
- Assist with content for marketing collateral, presentations, webinars, and sales training in support of the product.
- Drive large-scale initiatives from initial opportunity identification and research, to feasibility analysis and feature definition, all the way to business consumption and success metric tracking.

NextGen Healthcare • San Diego, CA • April 2016 to February 2018

Chief Technical Product Owner

- Lead multiple Scrum teams in developing business cases for EHR improvements.
- Gather requirements (MVP and MMF), translate concepts into wireframes and mockups, and build prototypes for usability testing.
- Guide and manage the development and delivery of online software products.
- Develop new opportunities and managed migrations of existing solutions to new hosting environment.
- Direct development teams to solve complex usability problems by devising elegant solutions.

Monarch Healthcare (OptumCare - UnitedHealth Group) • Irvine, CA • July 2015 to April 2016

EHR Application Analyst / Supervisor

- Provided leadership to Implementation and Business Analysts for improvements to the NextGen EHR software by evaluating recommendations.
- Created action plans, development of EHR templates, and oversaw weekly deployments.
- Managed multiple projects to ensure deadlines were met and tasks were completed in compliance with regulatory rules and internal guidelines.
- Prepared and presented training documentation to multiple departments for new product launches and process improvement initiatives.

HealthFusion, Inc • Solana Beach, CA • June 2014 to June 2015

Integration Manager/HL7 Engineer

- Accomplished department objectives by managing staff, planning and evaluating department activities, and implementing the integration of applications and solutions.
- Provided leadership for staff, clients, and vendors.
- Worked cooperatively with principals and supervisors with technology integration.

•	Designed, planned, and facilitated training for staff to meet technology skills.

Object Health (Elevation Point), LLC • San Diego, CA • July 2011 to March 2014

Senior Consultant

- Focused on privacy and security, electronic health record implementations, project management, and community health improvement projects.
- Executed the integration and coordination of activities and programs with key partners.
- Implemented computer software for practice management and electronic record system.

Clinicas de Salud del Pueblo, Inc • Brawley, CA • June 2010 to June 2011

Health Information Analyst

- Drove project management, implementation and maintenance of NextGen EHR in a 1-year roll-out.
- Delivered health management reporting and analysis, quality improvement, and community health improvements.

Imperial County and City of Brawley • Imperial Valley, CA • June 2004 to October 2010

Reserve Firefighter/Emergency Medical Technician

- Served as volunteer and paid Firefighter I/Emergency Medical Technician.
- Ensured protection of life, property, and environment through fire suppression, prevention, and ambulatory emergency medical care.

Education

Key Courses

Certified Agile Scrum Product Owner / Scrum Master, Construx & Scrum Institute

Certification of User Experience Design, University of California, San Diego - Extension Center

Front End Web Development Certification, University of California, San Diego - Extension Center

Nationally Registered Emergency Medical Technician - Intermediate Optional Scope, Imperial Valley College

Firefighter Engineer / EMT, Imperial County Fire Department

Skills

Agile, Scrum, Requirements Definition, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python, SQL, Usability Testing, User Experience Design, and User Interface Design.